<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Makeomatic Blog: Website, mobile application and design development</title>
  
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-08T17:55:52.000Z</updated>
  <id>https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Makeomatic</name>
    <email>getstarted@makeomatic.ru</email>
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Smart travelling network for the benefit of everyone</title>
    <link href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2015/12/18/Smart_travelling_network/"/>
    <id>https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2015/12/18/Smart_travelling_network/</id>
    <published>2015-12-18T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-08T17:55:52.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/blog/images/f4f_main.jpg" alt="Illustration Smart travelling"></p>
<p>Only one week left before we step into 2016. It’s been a productive year for Makeomatic. Not breaking the established tradition, we visited <a href="http://nodeconfeu.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">NodeConf</a> in Waterford. Throughout the year our team leaders coached two interns, one of them eventually joined and empowered the team. On a more serious side, we polished and shipped older products as well as plunged into several new challenges. We’ll tell you briefly about one of those and the technical decisions we made on the way.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>As digital era dictates its rules, the rise of several large e-commerce platforms such as Amazon and Shopify and a swarm of smaller players tested and proved that e-commerce has come here to stay. Furthermore, the way we scout for a particular thing to buy has evolved — we don’t go straight to the shop. Instead, we open a search engine, find what’s needed, and more than often order it right there. It’s easy, convenient and saves a lot of time. Most importantly, it allows one to order from abroad something that would never be available in a local shop. </p>
<p>However, when seeing the final shipping cost, often all you think is “thank you, but no, thank you”. This varies from country to country, but more often than not you would find that international shipping expenses are ridiculously high. Then, what we usually do  is go to our preferred social network and post a plea hoping that some of our friends will soon be on a trip and will generously help us get the desired goods. This would work at times, but it is, by far, not a bulletproof solution.</p>
<p>When a new client approached us with a task to build a local social platform connecting those, who want to get purchases from abroad and those, who will benefit from delivering them, we could relate to the need for such a start-up. So after discussing essential features and user flow, we set up to work.  </p>
<h3 id="Purpose-and-target-audience"><a href="#Purpose-and-target-audience" class="headerlink" title="Purpose and target audience"></a>Purpose and target audience</h3><p>At Makeomatic we try to be very precise about features from square one. This allows us not to spend months wireframing but rather jump right into creating UI that people are going to see. For this we need to determine the main problems which our product is going to solve, in other words, its main purpose. </p>
<p>In this particular case, we set on the task to build a social network for people that are fond of travelling or interested in getting particular goods from abroad. This means that we needed to build a robust platform — comfortable for social interactions, modern and easy to use for demanding yuppies and secure for online payments. Throughout all of our prototyping and building we kept that in mind.</p>
<p>It was decided to divide the development into three separate stages — a desktop web app, iOS and Android mobile apps.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/images/1.jpg" alt="1"></p>
<h3 id="First-steps-choosing-the-tools"><a href="#First-steps-choosing-the-tools" class="headerlink" title="First steps: choosing the tools"></a>First steps: choosing the tools</h3><p>The success of any start-up depends on a good idea, but, as far as we are concerned, and <a href="https://sivers.org/multiply" target="_blank" rel="external">others</a> agree, execution is what really matters. Every small architectural decision adds to the potential of the app. At Makeomatic we use a bunch of various technologies. Certainly, we have our favourites, and Node.js is definitely among them. </p>
<p>At NodeConf we’ve been told that Node.js beats most of the other programming languages in development speed and, often, performance by 2-4 times. There’s no better way to prove it than to switch from the old core languages, such as Java, Ruby or PHP, and use it in a real project. </p>
<p>From our experience we can safely claim that Node.js is the right choice for high load, data-intensive applications, and paired with a javascript framework on the frontend - (like Angular or React) it is suitable for supporting isomorphic Single-Page Applications as well. </p>
<p>What exactly is high-load, and how to understand if your product is going to be data-intensive?  We share the opinion that there is no universal tool for all cases. You wouldn’t drive a nail with a screwdriver, and you shouldn’t build a simple static blog with Node.js - of course you could as a proof-of-concept, but from a practical standpoint it would be “an overkill”. But if your product is a search network engine (like the one we’ve worked on and briefly described <a href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2015/11/27/people_search_engine">here</a> or if your app will be used by thousands of people simultaneously - Node.js is your best bet. That is why the first stage of our workflow is determining (and documenting) a list of all features - it gives us an overview of what a product is going to be in the end and what technical requirements should be taken care of in case we need to scale up.</p>
<p>Since our project is a social network, we knew that it was very likely to be a high-traffic application. It was also designed to be real-time: when a traveller or customer submits  information about a new trip or order, we needed to make these updates instantly available for all of our users. </p>
<p>Finally, private messaging is a must. All this sounds like a typical use case for Node.js. A reasonable choice that we combined with Babel.js transpiler so that our developers could take advantage of using the newest version of Javascript (ES6).  </p>
<p>As we strive to keep up-to-date with evolving technologies and modern industry solutions, it was settled that we would use a microservices architecture. The idea of it is that the application consists of loosely coupled functional units, which are easily reusable and interchangeable. Simply put, it means that the codebase is logically divided into small components (or modules) - every module is a small app in itself. This makes the architecture flexible: if at some point our social network evolves into a more complex platform or transforms in a different product, we won’t need to throw the whole codebase away and start from scratch. </p>
<p>Predictably, as a search engine for the project we chose ElasticSearch - an open source solution with a rich API that we’ve taken advantage of in the previous projects. This time it helped us to provide a quick and easy search by multiple facets (country, date, product category, etc.). If we organized an in-house contest “favourite Makeomatic tools”, ElasticSearch would certainly come second (after Node.js). We’re planning to write a separate article describing the problems it helped us solve.</p>
<h3 id="Frontend-what-the-users-will-see"><a href="#Frontend-what-the-users-will-see" class="headerlink" title="Frontend - what the users will see"></a>Frontend - what the users will see</h3><h4 id="Intuitive-UX"><a href="#Intuitive-UX" class="headerlink" title="Intuitive UX"></a>Intuitive UX</h4><p>Obviously, every social network starts with a profile: an avatar, last time seen, personal user’s information, private messages - the usual stuff. Our profiles had to include so much more: planned trips, orders, reviews and all of the associated metadata. The first challenge we faced was to group the main interface components in such a manner that would ensure easy navigation. We tried to hide less important blocks in a submenu but quickly realized it wouldn’t work. </p>
<p>A social network’s functionality is supposed to be intuitive. Users must not spend  hours to reveal all features of the app. Furthermore, help or FAQ sections must be a rarely used last resort option. Eventually, we encapsulated key information within tabs in the primary content area. On large screens user profiles display this information in one view, on mobile secondary features are hidden in navigation menu.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/images/2.jpg" alt="2"><br><img src="/blog/images/3.jpg" alt="3"></p>
<h4 id="Social-interactions"><a href="#Social-interactions" class="headerlink" title="Social interactions"></a>Social interactions</h4><p>What’s a social network without social interaction? Apart from private messaging, we integrated reviews and a rating system. This lets people leave a feedback on deals with other users, filtering out unreliable travellers or customers. The algorithm forming the ratings depends on different parameters, such as activity on the site, reviews, the amount of goods ordered and delivered.</p>
<p><img src="/blog/images/4.jpg" alt="4"></p>
<p>Those who say “the devil’s in the details”, know a thing or two. After a short round of usability testing, we realized that our social profiles lacked one small but important feature — traveller’s panel. When embarking on a trip people want to spend it in good company, a natural desire that explains the proliferation of sites for searching travel mates. </p>
<p>So our test users were expecting to see this feature as well. Without further delay we integrated the option into profiles, increasing social engagement and prompting people to return and use the platform more often. Apart from that, we added a “travelog” tab where people who have returned from a trip (and successfully delivered orders) could share their impressions. Among other things, these small improvements are beneficial for SMO (Social Media Optimization).</p>
<p><img src="/blog/images/5.png" alt="5"></p>
<h4 id="More-technical-aspects"><a href="#More-technical-aspects" class="headerlink" title="More technical aspects"></a>More technical aspects</h4><p>It would be unfair not to mention one more secret weapon in our toolbox . The client part of the travelling network was written with the help of the Angular.js framework. By now everyone has heard of this “magic technology” from Google. Of course, there’s more logic than magic in it — every tool becomes a powerful weapon once you master it. </p>
<p>At the beginning of the development cycle our team briefly considered different alternatives, and the final choice was Angular.js: this framework is maintained by huge community and backed by a monster corporation (so chances are high it won’t be abandoned and deprecated), it works really well with Node.js and MongoDB (our main database). To top it off, we’ve used the framework extensively in previous projects — and there’s no better friend than experience.</p>
<p>There were also minor decisions like choosing a tool for automating our build tasks (currently - Gulp), preprocessing styles (this time it’s Stylus) and a templating (Jade).</p>
<p>If you’ve read this far, you are probably a fan of modern web solutions. Or may be you are only considering which technologies to choose for your next mind-blowing start-up (if you need help - drop us a line, we’ll gladly consult you). But I won’t overwhelm you with technical aspects any longer. Because, whatever tools you opt-in  for, most importantly is whether your start-up, product or app solves real problems. If it does, it will find its users, no matter what. </p>
<p>As the e-commerce market thrives, people will get more interested in acquiring unusual things. While the government constantly plans to reduce the tax-free threshold for online purchases from abroad, we hope that the smart social network we’ve had the chance to work on will meet the need to connect those who are ready to help others, getting extra money as a bonus to their trip, and those in need of unavailable, exclusive things. </p>
<p>Merry Christmas and brilliant New Year 2016! The Makeomatic team wishes you to surf on the top of the digital wave and make all your ideas come to live.</p>
<p>To be continued…</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/f4f_main.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration Smart travelling&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one week left before we step into 2016. It’s been a productive year for Makeomatic. Not breaking the established tradition, we visited &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodeconfeu.com/&quot;&gt;NodeConf&lt;/a&gt; in Waterford. Throughout the year our team leaders coached two interns, one of them eventually joined and empowered the team. On a more serious side, we polished and shipped older products as well as plunged into several new challenges. We’ll tell you briefly about one of those and the technical decisions we made on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Elasticsearch" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/Elasticsearch/"/>
    
      <category term="NodeJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/NodeJS/"/>
    
      <category term="AngularJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/AngularJS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>People search engine like Google but for people</title>
    <link href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2015/11/27/people_search_engine/"/>
    <id>https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2015/11/27/people_search_engine/</id>
    <published>2015-11-27T08:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-08T17:55:52.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/blog/images/search_engine.png" alt="Illustration search engine"></p>
<p>A key activity of Makeomatic in the past year has been our involvement in people search engine. Today, we would like to show you briefly what this product is, and how Makeomatic have contributed to it. This is the first in a series of blog posts detailing our involvement with peoplefinders and showcasing our solutions to their questions and problems.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<h3 id="People-search-engine"><a href="#People-search-engine" class="headerlink" title="People search engine"></a>People search engine</h3><p>At first glance this product is a search engine, but that would hardly do it justice, because it can do so much more than your average search engine. First of all, it’s more specialised: it’s peoplefinders (and did you know that 30 percent of all Google searches are for people?), but it does so much more than just give you a list of websites where a name appears. This platform specifically searches more than 50 social networks, and it can connect the dots for you. It processes, aggregates and sorts the data it finds. </p>
<p>Therefore, when you’re searching for your old classmate Sam, wouldn’t it be great if the search engine returned a full metaprofile, with their Facebook likes, Instagram pics, LinkedIn info and latest tweets all in one place? Of course, that’s not an easy thing to do – this engine has to figure out that this Sam Miller on Facebook is the same person as that Sam Miller on Google+, for example. This requires some nifty algorithms working for you behind the scenes, and this is  where Makeomatic enter the picture.</p>
<h3 id="Distributed-content-analysis-and-Data-Mining-solutions"><a href="#Distributed-content-analysis-and-Data-Mining-solutions" class="headerlink" title="Distributed content analysis and Data Mining solutions"></a>Distributed content analysis and Data Mining solutions</h3><p>In the past year, Makeomatic have provided a good deal of the physical and computational infrastructure behind the search engine with Nodejs and Elasticsearch technologies, to allow the system to run as smoothly and quickly as possible. We migrated their system from AWS to in-house Data Center with more than 100 servers running day and night. Elasticsearch made it possible to process 100,000 parallel search requests while keeping the search speed below 500 milliseconds. We also integrated CI (Continuous Integration) into the search engine’s everyday workflow. And not to forget, we put our brains behind data mining, helping to aggregate the people data scattered across a wide range of social sites.</p>
<h3 id="Social-networking-tools"><a href="#Social-networking-tools" class="headerlink" title="Social networking tools"></a>Social networking tools</h3><p>While a general browser-based search engine is not online yet, this platform has published several products that use its database. Makeomatic made a mail client available as an app, and we developed a browser plugin for your e-mail account. Both share one unique feature: they link your mail contacts with their social network information. Not to forget, we also contributed to REST API, an interface to access our database and to conduct searches, making it even more efficient.</p>
<h3 id="Using-the-people-search-engine"><a href="#Using-the-people-search-engine" class="headerlink" title="Using the people search engine"></a>Using the people search engine</h3><p>You can download Mail client, which is free, to help you organise your mail more efficiently and to link up your mail contacts with your social network contacts. In addition, there are a range of corporate customers, who have integrated the people search engine’s API into their systems. Imagine you had a new customer or a potential new employee — wouldn’t it be nice to have aggregate information about them at your fingertips, rather than spending a lot of time trying to google that information? Or imagine you’re company interested in targeted advertising – with the people profiles this project builds you stand a much better chance that your message also reaches the intended recipient.</p>
<h3 id="Looking-forward"><a href="#Looking-forward" class="headerlink" title="Looking forward"></a>Looking forward</h3><p>It is clear as daylight that social networks have become a customary part of their daily routine for billions of people. Every second they are gaining more and more users, sharing their views, opinions, likes and dislikes and inevitably enriching the quality and the quantity of unprecedented amount of valuable data, and this is one of the biggest challenges of the present time. Facing it is only possible with the help of a powerful tool designed and created by the most up-to-date breakthrough technologies like AngularJS and NodeJS. </p>
<p>In today’s post we wanted to give you an idea of what the people search engine is and how we at Makeomatic contributed to making this project what it is. Later on, there will be a series of blog posts explaining in greater detail what Makeomatic have done to make this product fruitful.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/search_engine.png&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration search engine&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key activity of Makeomatic in the past year has been our involvement in people search engine. Today, we would like to show you briefly what this product is, and how Makeomatic have contributed to it. This is the first in a series of blog posts detailing our involvement with peoplefinders and showcasing our solutions to their questions and problems.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Elasticsearch" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/Elasticsearch/"/>
    
      <category term="NodeJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/NodeJS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hacking the code of international shipping</title>
    <link href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2014/07/30/elasticsearch_distribut/"/>
    <id>https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2014/07/30/elasticsearch_distribut/</id>
    <published>2014-07-30T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-08T17:55:52.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/blog/images/elastic_distribut.png" alt="Illustration Distribut.io"></p>
<p>Addressing issues and solving problems, people and businesses are facing in their everyday routine, no matter how challenging they are, has always been usual practice for us at Makeomatic. But when a client with more than 15 years of experience in international shipping turned to us asking for help, at first we were frozen with shock — we had no idea of how intricate and sometimes misleading the process of worldwide logistics could be. It took us time and effort to investigate this question in great detail and get back to the client with the solution. We proposed a technical concept using new technologies, such as elasticseach, angular.js and node.js. In the end we managed to obtain a simple search engine of Harmonized System codes.<br><a id="more"></a></p>
<p>###Search for a shipping code</p>
<p>This solution created by Makeomatic is now a part of Distribut.io, which is capable of doing many things in order to save user’s time with his or her international shipping paperwork. But there is one thing, which really does the trick — it can efficiently search through thousands of custom codes and regulations. Thanks to <a href="http://www.elasticsearch.org/" target="_blank" rel="external">Elasticsearch</a>, an open source search engine that strives on analyzing data. Our technical decision doesn’t merely process data, it also possesses features of the artificial intelligence. Elasticsearch is capable of searching through millions of data entries, which is why it is used by such online giants as Foursquare, an audio distribution platform Soundcloud, a social network for developpers GitHub, a recommendation service StumbleUpon and many more. The best search engine analyzes data in real-time and offers a full text search. And this great power now works for the benefit of Distribut.io’s users.</p>
<p>Elasticsearch is what allows Distribut.io search through the international customs tarriffs, an internationally standardized system of names and numbers to classify traded products, known as Harmonized System (HS) codes. The HS code is organized into 21 sections and 96 chapters, accompanied with general rules of interpretation and explanatory notes, making a manual search a daunting task.</p>
<p>This is an HS code list in its regular format. How quickly can you find the subheading 1602 10, 1602 50 31 or 1602 50 95 in order to determine if your exported goods meet this particular HS code?</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">0206299132 10,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - ,Other</div><div class="line">0206299132 20,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - ,&quot;Thin skirt, whole&quot;</div><div class="line">0206299132 30,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - ,Intended for processing</div><div class="line">0206299132 80,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - - ,&quot;For the manufacture of products falling within subheadings 1602 10, 1602 50 31 or 1602 50 95, not containing meat other than that of animals of the bovine species, with a collagen/protein ratio of no more than 0,45 and containing by weight at least 20% of lean meat (excluding offal and fat) with meat and jelly accounting for at least 85% of the total net weight	 the products must be subjected to a heat treatment sufficient to ensure the coagulation of meat proteins in the whole of the product and which therefore shows no traces of a pinkish liquid on the cut surface when the product is cut along a line passing through its thickest part (A-products)&quot;</div><div class="line">0206299134 80,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - - ,&quot;For the manufacture of products other than those falling within subheadings ex 0210 20, 0210 99 51, 0210 99 90, 1602 50 10 and 1602 90 61 (B-products)&quot;</div><div class="line">0206299136 80,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - - ,Other</div><div class="line">0206299139 80,01/01/89 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - ,Other</div><div class="line">0206299150 10,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - ,Other</div><div class="line">0206299150 20,07/01/96 12:00 AM,,EN,10,- - - - - - - ,Intended for processing</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>What if those references that had taken you such great pains to find, in turn, contain still more references, sending you on another chase? By the time you have found the correct answer in the bureaucratic maze of HS codes, you will have wasted precious time and resources that could have been spent elsewhere.</p>
<p>With Distribut.io, this task is no longer cumbersome, frustrating and inefficient. It frees a user from the need to compare and contrast the HS codes. With the help of the elasticsearch, Distribut.io offers an effective way to pick the right HS code for the right product, saving time and money and allowing the small business owner to focus on growing his or her business.</p>
<p>If you find our ideas and their realization elegant and smart, we would gladly help you out with your project.  </p>
<h4 id="Developing-your-idea-with-Makeomatic"><a href="#Developing-your-idea-with-Makeomatic" class="headerlink" title="Developing your idea with Makeomatic"></a>Developing your idea with Makeomatic</h4><p>You can drop us an email to <a href="mailto:getstarted@makeomatic.ru" target="_blank" rel="external">getstarted@makeomatic.ru</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/elastic_distribut.png&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration Distribut.io&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addressing issues and solving problems, people and businesses are facing in their everyday routine, no matter how challenging they are, has always been usual practice for us at Makeomatic. But when a client with more than 15 years of experience in international shipping turned to us asking for help, at first we were frozen with shock — we had no idea of how intricate and sometimes misleading the process of worldwide logistics could be. It took us time and effort to investigate this question in great detail and get back to the client with the solution. We proposed a technical concept using new technologies, such as elasticseach, angular.js and node.js. In the end we managed to obtain a simple search engine of Harmonized System codes.&lt;br&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Elasticsearch" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/Elasticsearch/"/>
    
      <category term="NodeJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/NodeJS/"/>
    
      <category term="AngularJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/AngularJS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Shipping abroad — as good as it gets!</title>
    <link href="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2014/07/18/Shipping_abroad/"/>
    <id>https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2014/07/18/Shipping_abroad/</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-08T17:55:52.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/blog/images/dist.io.png" alt="Illustration Distribut.io"></p>
<p>Overburdened with paperwork, many ambitious and hard-working entrepreneurs across the Globe willing to take their growing business beyond the boundaries of their countries, face spending time and money on filling out necessary documents, obtaining customs declarations in order to ship their products on the international markets. Anyone who had to go through this costly process at least once knows well what a waste of time and effort it is.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>In an archaic and complicated world of worldwide shipping, an average small business is forced to spend a lot of time navigating numberless custom rules, regulations and duties of many different countries. It cannot afford to fill out delivery slips by hand for each and every shipment. Big corporations are used to turn a blind eye to paying substantial amounts to lawyers in order to make their international logistics legally compliant. However small online business owners cannot afford to do that. They lack capital and necessary resources to drag their paperwork through the complex world of the international postage. And therefore, they cannot as easily access the global market as the large companies. It stifles their growth and limits their expansion opportunities.  </p>
<h3 id="This-is-where-Distribut-io-comes-in"><a href="#This-is-where-Distribut-io-comes-in" class="headerlink" title="This is where Distribut.io comes in"></a>This is where Distribut.io comes in</h3><p>A start-up called <a href="http://distribut.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Distribut.io</a> believes the process of shipment should neither be complicated nor should it involve a lot of superfluous documents. This belief drove the company to create a solution to this problem. This startup offers small business owners worldwide – specifically online store sellers – a cheaper opportunity to easily tap the global markets for their merchandize or services. This service would allow a talented designer in Nairobi, where the global logistics is a nightmare, to send her designed jewelry to China, South America, the United States or Europe with a push of a button.   Distribut.io aims to simplify the international shipment processing for small business owners. No more filling out delivery slips. No more entering an appropriate custom codes by hand. No more expensive legal advice.</p>
<h4 id="International-shipping-RESTful-API-for-your-company"><a href="#International-shipping-RESTful-API-for-your-company" class="headerlink" title="International shipping RESTful API for your company"></a>International shipping RESTful API for your company</h4><p>With Distribut.io, the process is smooth and hassle-free. The company offers an application programming interface, commonly known as an API, to online vendors in order to apply the company’s intelligence for the small businesses benefit.</p>
<p>Distribut.io provides REST API’s on a scalable and dynamic cloud platform that enables e-commerce and logistics applications on the web, mobile or desktop flexible access to multiple currencies, international address verification system, affordable international shipping rates with tracking, duties and taxes, and to an international returns management network. All services are offered on the same platform simultaneously. It is easy to use with its simple implementation with API’s and open source plugins. There are flexible API’s purchase plans clients can choose from. The API can easily be implemented with inventory, e-commerce or multi-channel sales applications on almost any platform.</p>
<p>Distribut.io will worry about all the regulation, currency exchange rates, taxes, and duties giving a small business owner the opportunity to focus on what he or she can do best, innovating, developing their business and growing their customer base through previously-untapped markets.</p>
<p>Currently, Distribut.io is in beta-testing, offering b2b services between the European Union and the United States. However, in the future, it plans to expand its shipping services to other parts of the world. There is no doubt it won’t take long and the outdated routine of international shipping will undergo a dramatic change it has been awaiting for such a long time.</p>
<p>Continue to the next part of the story:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="//en.makeomatic.ru/blog/2014/07/30/elasticsearch_distribut/">Hacking the code of international shipping</a></li>
</ul>
<h5 id="Developing-your-idea-with-Makeomatic"><a href="#Developing-your-idea-with-Makeomatic" class="headerlink" title="Developing your idea with Makeomatic"></a>Developing your idea with Makeomatic</h5><p>You can drop us an email to <a href="mailto:getstarted@makeomatic.ru" target="_blank" rel="external">getstarted@makeomatic.ru</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/dist.io.png&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration Distribut.io&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overburdened with paperwork, many ambitious and hard-working entrepreneurs across the Globe willing to take their growing business beyond the boundaries of their countries, face spending time and money on filling out necessary documents, obtaining customs declarations in order to ship their products on the international markets. Anyone who had to go through this costly process at least once knows well what a waste of time and effort it is.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Elasticsearch" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/Elasticsearch/"/>
    
      <category term="NodeJS" scheme="https://en.makeomatic.ru/blog/tags/NodeJS/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
